In this lesson, we'll go
over one of the main use cases
that we see developers using OpenAI
functions for, tagging and extraction.
This allows us to extract
structured data from unstructured text.
Let's have some fun.
The first use case that
we'll cover is tagging.
In tagging, we pass in
an unstructured piece of
text along with some
structured description,
and then we use the LLM to
generate some structured
output to reason over that input text
and create some
response in the format of the
structured description that we pass in.
So here in this example, we know that
we want to be generating an object that
has a sentiment of the text and also
has a tag for the language of the text.
And so when we pass in a piece
of text we'll pass in a structure
description saying hey
extract some sentiment,
extract some language, and the LLM
will reason over that text and respond
with an object that has a
sentiment tag and a language tag.
This is similar but
slightly different from the second
use case that we'll
cover, which is extraction.
In extraction, we're going to be
extracting specific entities from the text.
These entities are also
represented by a structure description.
But rather than using the LLM to
reason over the text and respond
with a single output in
this structure description.
We're using the LLM to look over the
text and extract a list of these elements.
So we might ask it to look
over an article and extract a
list of the papers that were
mentioned in that article.
Let's take a look at doing this in code.
First we're going to
import our standard setup.
We're then going to import
some of the functions and
classes that we learned
about in the last lesson.
So we're going to import list from
typing to help us with type hints.
We're going to import base
model and field from Pydantic.
And then we're going to import our
convert Pydantic to open AI function.
Let's now create a Pydantic model
that we're going to use for tagging.
So we're going to call it tagging,
we're going to have a
description where we just
say tag the piece of
text with particular info,
and then we're going to
have a list of the attributes
that we want to tag the text with.
So first sentiment, and
we're going to have the
description be the sentiment of the text,
should be pause, neg, or neutral.
So we're defining some values
that the sentiment field should be,
and remember this gets
passed into the language model,
so this is how we're telling
the language model what the
shape of the data that
we're extracting should be.
And then we also have a language tag.
And here we have the
language of the text and we're
again saying it should be
in this ISO 639-1 code.
If we then call our
"convert_pydantic_to_openai_function" method on this class,
So let's now use this to actually do
the tagging. What are we going to need?
We're going to need two more things.
We're going to need a
prompt in a language model.
So we're going to import a chat
prompt template in our chat OpenAI model.
We'll create our model really simply
by setting temperature equals to zero.
And we're going to do this
because when we're tagging things
we generally want it to
be pretty deterministic.
We're then going to create
our tagging functions which
are just going to be a
single one at this point,
We're going to add in a pretty
simple system message to start.
And then we'll add in a spot where
we're going to pass in the user input.
We're then going to create a
model with functions so we're
going to bind the model
to the tagging functions,
We can then create a
tagging chain by just combining
the prompt with this model
and then we can call this.
And then we can call this on a piece
of text and we can get back a response.
And so we're calling the tagging function.
We can see that the function call is
there and then we can see the arguments that
are passed in and we can see that
sentiment is positive and language is English.
We can do this for another piece of text.
We can vary it up and try a different
language and a different sentiment.
So let's do some Italian.
So as you can see we're getting the
language model to respond in this format but it's still kind of nested here in
this additional quarks bit and
we know that we're always going
to be extracting the
structure and so what we really
want to do is add an output
parser that takes in this AI
message and basically parses
out the JSON and just says
that because that's the only
interesting thing here we already
know that we're going to
be calling this function.
So the fact that content is
null, that's not interesting to us.
The fact that there's a function call
that's made, that's not interesting to us.
We're forcing it to do that. The fact
that it's calling the tagging function,
also not interesting to us
because we know that it's going
to be calling the tagging
function because we forced it to.
And so here what we really want is just
the value of arguments, which is JSON blob,
and it'll be really convenient if
that was parsed into JSON because
it's JSON in this JSON blob
and we want to be able to
use the individual elements and
so we have a nice little output
parser in link chain that
can help with exactly that.
It's called JSON output functions parser
and so we'll import it from LangChain output parsers open AI functions
And so this is much more nice and
convenient to work with downstream.
Let's now go into extraction. And
extraction is similar to tagging,
but we want to use it to extract
multiple pieces of information.
First, we'll define the piece of
information that we want to extract.
And this is a person schema. So,
we'll have information about a person,
What we want to do is we want to
extract a list of these objects,
and so we'll define another
class called information,
which is just the
information that we want to extract.
We'll add an attribute
which is people and then
this will be a list of the person type.
This information class
is going to be the one
that we're passing in
as the open AI function.
So here we can convert that
class to open AI functions
and we can see that we
have information properties.
The main property is people and
then if we look at the description
of people we can see that we now
have the person description here.
So under the hood in this
convert Pydantic to Open AI
So now we're going to set up
our extraction chain. First,
Next we're going to set
up the extraction model.
So we're going to bind functions
equal to extraction functions because
we want to use those and then
we're going to bind function
call with name set equal to
information because the name of the
function that we want to force
the model to call is information.
After that we can try it out.
So let's try it out on a simple sentence,
His mom is Martha.
So now there's two people here.
And we can see that what it
extracts is name Joe, age 30.
Gets a second person this
time, name Martha, age 0.
Which probably we can do better.
We can force the model to
respond in a more educated way.
And so what we're going to do
is we're going to add a prompt
that's going to tell the
language model to do that.
So now we're adding a prompt and we have
a system message where we say extract the
relevant information if not explicitly
provided do not guess extract partial info.
So hopefully what this
should do is this should force
the language model or
this should allow the
language model to not
respond always with an age
it's not going to make
up this age equals zero.
So we can create a new
extraction chain as this prompt,
and then the extraction model.
And if we call this
extraction chain on the same thing,
we can now see that in the
arguments, we have name Martha,
and there's nothing mentioned
about age so it's correctly reasoning
that it doesn't need to
pass in information about age.
Again we can probably do
better than just this AI message
we can try to parse it
into some structure.
So let's add back in that JSON
output parser that we had before.
If we call it again, we can
see that it's parsed into this
For extraction, though,
there's again some extraneous
information here that
we don't really need.
We don't really care that
there's this list of people here.
Because remember, when we defined it,
information is just a
vehicle to allow us to extract
multiple elements of this person field.
What we really care about
is just this list of person.
So we can use a different
output parser for that.
We can import JSON key
output functions parser.
And what this will
basically do is it will look for a
particular key in the
output and extract only that.
So now we modify our
extraction chain slightly.
We pass in this new output parser
and we pass it in with a key name
equal to people because this is
the field that we want to extract.
Now if we call this on the input again,
we can see that now we just have this list.
So it's a minor improvement but it
will make it easier to use downstream
if extraction is truly what we
care about for this purpose.
Now is a good time to pause and play
around with both tagging and extraction.
Add some different models,
try some different input text.
There's a lot of cool
things you can do here.
We're going to put this all together
into a slightly more real world example.
So what we're going to
do is we're first going
to load a real article from the internet.
So we're going to use a
web-based loader which
comes from LangChain Document Loaders,
And so we're going to
pass in this URL here,
which is a great blog post
about autonomous agents.
We're going to call.load, and this
is going to load a few documents.
It's going to load 1
document in particular,
So what we're first
going to do is we're going
to get the first
10,000 characters of this.
If we print out the first few
bit of this page content, again,
we're not going to print it all
out because it's pretty long.
But if we print out the beginning,
we can see that it's an article
about LLM powered autonomous agents.
And then we could probably do a
little bit better cleanup of this,
but we'll work with this text as is.
So we can see that it
starts to finally get down
into some introduction
or some overview section.
And so we're going to work with this
text to do both tagging and extraction.
First, we're going to create a
class describing what we want to tag.
So we want to get an overview of this
article. And so we want to extract a summary,
the language that's
used, and any keywords.
And so we're going to create this nice
model that we can use to describe all that.
We're then going to set up the chain
and this is all very similar to above.
So we're going to create the
overview tagging functions
and this is just
converting one base model,
the overview base model, to open
AI functions using this method.
We're then going to
create our tagging model.
So we're going to bind the
functions that we created
above and force it to call this overview.
And then we're going to create a
tagging chain. So we're doing a prompt,
which is the prompt that we
used above, a tagging model,
and then JSON output functions parser.
Putting that all together,
we can now call
"tagging_chain.invoke" and we can
And so we can see that it
extracts a summary of the article.
This article discusses the concept of
building autonomous agents powered by LLMs.
It's in English and extracted a bunch
of keywords. LLM, autonomous agents,
planning, memory, tool use, task,
decomposition, self-reflection.
Now we're going to try to extract all
papers that are mentioned by this article.
And this article is very
good and very academic,
and so it mentions a lot of papers.
And we're really interested what
the papers that it mentioned are.
So we'll create some base
models here. First up is paper.
We want to know the title
of the paper and then the
author of the paper as
well if it's provided.
And then we are going to put this inside
another class called info and we're going
to have papers be a list of paper so
that we can get a lot of them back.
We're then going to set up our
extraction chain and so here we're
creating the functions that we
want to pass in which is just info.
We're then binding that to
the functions parameter or then
binding function call and
setting name equal to info.
We're going to force it to
call this info function,
So we're going to create that and then we
can run it on the page content once again.
And so we can see that we
get one result back title
LLM powered autonomous
agents author Lillian Weng.
And so this is a little
bit confusing because
this is actually the title of the article
that we're passing in and the author
of the article that we're passing in.
It's not the papers that are mentioned
within the article, it's the article itself.
And so the language model is
probably getting confused because if you
remember the the initial page is a
lot of this is the article title,
this is the author, and we haven't really
instructed the language model too clearly
that it should be extracting rather than
the information about the article itself,
it should be extracting the
papers that are mentioned within.
And so in order to fix that,
we're going to give it a
slightly better system message.
So we're going to tell it more
explicitly, an article will be passed to you.
Extract from it all papers that
are mentioned by this article.
Do not extract the name
of the article itself.
If no papers are mentioned, that's
fine. You don't need to extract any,
just return an empty list.
Do not make up or guess
any extra information,
only extract exactly what is in the text.
And so we're going to create
this prompt that is much more
descriptive in how the
language model should behave.
We're going to use this prompt in our
new chain. Other than that, it's the same.
So it's got the same extraction
model, the same output parser.
And then we're going to call this new
chain on that page content and we're going
to get back a list of articles with
titles and authors and these look much
more reasonable and so these are all
great papers in this space that are not
the article itself but rather the
author is using to make some points.
We can also do some sanity checks to
make sure that it's performing okay.
So we can pass in a simple
message like hi we'd expect this
to return an empty list and
indeed it does and so here are
instructions about just
returning empty lists if there's
no papers that are mentioned
that they're working okay.
So it seems to be doing
a reasonable pass here.
Remember though, this is just the
first 10,000 characters of the article.
What if we want to do it on
the whole article and extract
all the papers that are
mentioned in the whole article?
In order to do that, we'll use some more
concepts, this time around text splitting.
So we're going to define a text splitter,
and we're going to use the
recursive character text splitter.
We covered this in the
previous course on deep learning.
So if this is unfamiliar,
I would check that out.
And the reason that we need
to do this text splitting
is that this article
is really really long.
And so if we try to pass that
article to the language model directly,
it's actually going to be
too big for the token window.
And so what we're going to do
is we're going to split it into
smaller pieces of text and
then we're going to pass those
pieces of text to the
language model individually and then
we're going to combine
all the results at the end.
So let's create some
splits by calling split
text on the page content of the document.
And if we look at how many splits we have,
we can see that we
have 14 different splits.
And so what we're going to try to do now
is we're going to create an entire chain
using LangChain Expression Language
that does everything that I just said.
We're going to take in this page content,
we're then going to
split it up into splits.
We're then going to pass all those
individual splits to the extraction chain that
we've defined above and then we're
going to join all the results together.
And so one thing that we'll
definitely need to do is we'll
need to create a function
that can join lists of lists.
And so we're going to create
this flatten function here.
And this just very simply takes in
a list of lists and flattens them.
So if we do flatten on,
let's do a list of 1, 2.
And then we have a second
element, which is a list of 3, 4,
And this is useful because we're
going to extract a list of papers
mentioned for each split and
then merge them all together.
The other thing that we're
going to need to do is have some
method of preparing the splits
to be passed into the chain.
So remember the chain
takes in an input variable and
specifically you need a
dictionary with an input key.
This list of splits if we look
at the first one, its just text.
So we're going to need some way of
taking this list of text and converting
it into a list of dictionaries
where that text is now the input key.
We're going to do that
by defining a function
for that because this is going to be the
first function that
happens in the chain we're
going to wrap it in a runnable lambda.
So a runnable lambda is just a
simple wrapper in LangChain that takes in
So we're going to define this
pre-processing function here.
So this is constructing a lambda where
it takes as input and we want to pass
the document as input or rather the
page content of the document as input.
So the x here is going to be
a string and what we're doing
is we're creating a
function that takes that string,
splits and constructs a list
of dictionaries where each
dictionary is an input
corresponding to the split.
If we play around with
this and see what it does,
we can call it on a string and we
get back a list of dictionaries.
Here there's just one
dictionary because the text splitter
doesn't split it up
because this text is very short,
but basically it's taking in
this string, splitting it up,
and creating a list of
dictionaries and the reason
that this is necessary is
because this is going to
be the input to the next
part the extraction chain
and so we want to create
a bunch of inputs there.
So now we can create our chain.
So we're going to have this prep function.
We then want to pass this
to the extraction chain.
But remember, the extraction
chain operates over a single element.
And here we have a list of
elements that we want to pass in.
So what we can do is we can
call .map on the extraction chain.
And this is basically
saying, take the previous input,
which here is going to be a list of
elements, and map this chain over them.
And so that's going to lead to a list of
lists because again this extraction chain
is returning a list as we defined it
and so we're going to call flatten on it.
And fly in here this can just be the
normal function that we defined above.
We don't need to wrap it in
a runnable lambda because
it's not the first one in the sequence.
We could if we wanted to
but it's not necessary.
So here we have this chain
and if we call chain.invoke and
we'll pass in the whole
page content of the document,
When it passes it to the
extraction chain it's actually
parallelizing a lot of
those calls automatically.
The default that it
parallelizes by is 5 calls.
So it's not fully parallelizing, but
it's speeding up a significant amount.
When all of those calls are done,
it will then get passed into
the final flatten function.
And there we go. It returns a
list of papers that it extracted.
So it's got the title
and it's got the author.
If we skim through, we can see that it's
leaving the author empty for some of them.
If we really wanted to tell it
to just omit that completely,
we could go back and change the prompt.
We can scroll down.
We can see here that it seems to be
making some up. So there's paper A, author A.
This appears to be incorrect,
but if you actually look at the
article that this is referencing,
this article is itself an article
about prompting and about, and covers,
among other things, extraction and
retrieval augmented generation and citing things.
And so there's actually a bunch of
language in there that's imitating
some fake papers and
having the response cite those,
and so it's actually
picking this up correctly.
One really interesting thing
is that when you do extraction
or even when you do
question answering over
articles that talk about
prompting or talk about language
models and have
examples of prompts in there,
sometimes the language
model can get confused
and mess things up, but that's an aside.
That wraps up the end-to-end example here.
This is a good time to pause and try
it out on other real-world examples.
Try it out on a PDF and
extract some information from that.
Try it out on another web page, mess
around with what you want to extract.
Tagging and extraction are some of the
most popular use cases for this structured
data extraction and so gaining
familiarity with this will go a long way.
In the next class, we'll talk
about something slightly different.
We'll talk about using OpenAI
functions not for extraction
but for deciding what functions to call.
See you there.